It can't be damaged by spirit energy.
Then...
Magic doesn't work either.
And the exit's disappeared.
A boss room...
And one of the ones where you can't
escape unless you defeat the boss?
Man... What horrible luck.
But even so...
I'm an adventurer, which means I'll
fight to the end without giving up!
I don't know if my sword will hold, but if
it's an undead, divinity should work on it!
You awake?
Existential
Evolution
Yeah...
Oh, right! There was this huge skeleton...
The most I can do is patch you up.
No... thank you.
You defeated it?
Yeah.
I-It's huge!
If it had a magic stone of this size,
it must've been an incredibly
powerful monster!
You're incredible.
I was lucky.
You can have it, if you want.
Are you serious?
Not without condition, though.
What do you want?
I can't see how somebody like me could be
of use to a powerful adventurer like you.
This is what I look like now.
A monster got me.
I can't go into the shops, or the guild.
I want you to do that for me.
Sure, even I can do that.
But is that really all you need?
The deal seems one-sided in my favor.
Then one more thing.
Let me eat and drink at your
restaurant whenever I want.
For free.
Are you stupid or something?
Eat all you want...
I won't let my restaurant
go bankrupt this time!
I'll work extra hard!
Thanks so much, mister!
Here.
We're going home.
O-Okay...
But how?
Go over there.
There's nothing there.
So he can't see the magic circles.
It should take you back
to where we came from.
Gotcha.
If you say it, I believe it.
I want to go on ahead...
But it'll have to be another time.
This is my restaurant,
the Red Dragon Tavern.
It's cleaner than I thought.
Maybe the food's so bad it kills you?
Honey, you're safe!
Ow...
Are you hurt?
We have to call a doctor!
Calm down, Isabelle.
I'm fine.
I got a little hurt, but he patched me up.
Oh, how silly of me.
He saved my life.
Oh, also...
Just look at this!
Th-That's...
Amazing, huh? He gave it to me!
No!
If you get tricked again... we
don't have anything left to pay...
Isabelle, it's true.
He may not look it, but
he's actually a great guy.
He heard about my debt
and decided to help me.
Of course, not for free.
I'm going to be helping him from now on.
Will you be doing something dangerous again?
It'll be fine. Just errands.
And I promised he can eat here for free.
But that's barely anything...
It's true.
Then...
Yeah.
I know I worried you, but it's okay now.
Oh, I never did introduce myself.
I'm Lorris. Lorris Cariello.
And this is...
Isabelle.
Thank you so much.
Don't worry about it.
Farewell.
You're leaving already, mister?
You saved my life. At
least tell me your name!
Can you promise you won't tell anybody?
Yeah.
I'll keep it a secret. And I'll
keep calling you "mister."
Rentt.
Thanks, Mister.
Come for a meal any time you like!
We'll be happy to have you!
It's a shame...
If he was a liar...
Just a villain with no family...
That would've been so much better.
I'd rather test it on someone evil.
That's why I didn't ask his name.
It's such a shame...
Lorraine...
No... What am I...?
You're a bit late.
How was the labyrinth?
Did you see the dragon?
No...
Oh, where did you put the
letters I got from the empire?
I need to answer them,
or the old men are gonna come
and break down my door.
What's wrong?
Was there a problem?
You don't sound so good.
That's not true.
I'm happy...
Oh? Did something good happen?
R-Rentt?
What happened?
Are you drunk?
No, I guess an undead can't get drunk.
Lorraine, I...
Y-Yeah? What?
Rentt...
R-Rentt!
You...
D-Delicious!
Rentt... are you still in there?
Rentt!
Good... you're still there, then.
In that case...
You're alive, right?
For now, sleep.
I'll hear your apology when you wake up.
If you're going to grab me like
that, do it when you're sober.
You can devour me any time you like.
What was I...?
Are you awake, Rentt?
Yeah. My head...
I was in the labyrinth...
Do you feel like something
strange is in control of you?
Or giving you strange impulses?
Very good, then.
Lorraine, I'm sorry.
I'll accept your apology.
But there's nothing to worry about.
It was an unpleasant accident.
That's all.
But that's not...
I'm more interested in
how much you remember.
I remember attacking you.
No... I met a man in the labyrinth,
and he looked delicious to me...
I started going crazy.
And you looked so delicious,
I couldn't help myself...
I expected this, to a degree.
You did?
Yes.
Ghouls prefer the flesh and blood of humans.
More importantly, is your body okay?
I almost never hold back.
It seems okay.
I'm glad.
But you took damage, I'm sure.
So rest quietly.
I will too.
Lorraine...
Let me see it.
I'd just sold all my potions
to the magical pharmacy.
Don't worry.
Once I get the ingredients in the
morning, I'll make one right away.
Let me take care of it.
You can use that much divinity?
Yeah.
I should be able to do basic healing.
I've never been healed by divinity before.
It feels nice. It's warm.
Well?
Yeah, the pain's gone.
This is amazing. It's all better.
Not yet.
I guess I can't pretend to
be damaged goods anymore.
Don't worry about it.
You...
At this point, you might be able
to pass it off as old wounds.
What about my face?
The mask has changed form!
What, you didn't notice?
When did that happen?
I'll need to hide this...
That mask isn't just cursed, I don't think.
Is it responding to your desires?
Let me try.
That's rare.
I've heard of magical swords
with wills of their own.
If you can control it,
maybe you can take it off?
I see...
Come off... Come off!
Can I try pulling on it?
Yes.
No luck.
Well, that's not entirely great.
Though, your face is still like an undead's.
You'll need to hide it for a while anyway.
Yeah.
I'll stay like this for a while.
Your words are a lot clearer now, too.
Yeah, it's much easier to talk.
Did I existential evolve?
I would assume so.
I defeated a strong monster, yes, but...
Last time, I evolved right
after I defeated the monster.
Perhaps it was because you
fed on my blood and flesh?
It's not that strange an idea.
You're not a ghoul anymore.
You're closer to a ghast.
A ghast?
I've almost never seen one... but
they're servants of vampires, right?
Yes.
They're weaker than even a lesser vampire.
And that's what you look like right now.
But why a ghast?
Even among us academics,
existential evolution is just like
the origins of the labyrinth itself.
A complete mystery.
But...
Rentt, would you like to hear my hypothesis?
Yes, please, tell me!
All right, I'll tell you.
Of course, I would've told
you even if you'd refused.
Don't fall asleep.
Now then, where to begin...
I didn't see it, but you were
a skeleton at first, right?
Yeah, that was... interesting.
And then you became a ghoul.
Yes.
Don't you think it's strange that
you'd go from a skeleton to a ghoul?
Existential evolution is when a monster
transforms into a more powerful being.
Well, that's the current definition,
regardless of what the exact truth is.
That's right.
So is a ghoul the only monster
superior to a skeleton?
Well, there's a skeleton soldier, a skeleton
knight... there's a lot of things.
There are reports of skeletons
becoming ghouls, yes.
But as for whether that's a coincidence,
or if there's some reason...
We know nothing!
But there's one thing we can infer.
The monster is evolving into
the form it wishes to take.
You kept saying you wanted
to become more human, didn't you?
That's right.
But then couldn't I have become
a vampire instead of a ghast?
A vampire looks more human.
It's probably like the adventurer's guild.
You can't jump from Iron to Gold, can you?
There must be conditions and
aptitudes that you need to meet.
I see!
Experiments using smaller monsters
have shown they existential evolve into
a form adapted to their environment.
In a volcanic area, to a form
with high fire affinity,
near water, to a form with
high water affinity.
It's possible that this evolution was a
passive reaction to their environment.
But if it happened in response
to the monster's will...?
There are some leaps of logic there, but it
seems to me like you have that potential.
Which means if I work hard enough,
I might become a vampire someday?
And someday... go back to being human?
The former I can say is a possibility.
The latter, I have no idea.
Of course.
I imagine that any further
existential evolutions
will involve more than
just defeating monsters.
I see...
Just like how I became a ghast by
ingesting your flesh and blood,
there must be some condition
for becoming a vampire.
Yeah. I think that's the case.
There's so much we don't know.
What did you expect?
Even what I just said is just a hypothesis.
You could even call it a fantasy.
It's a long road ahead, either way.
I'll help you as best I can.
Thank you.
Don't worry about it.
Now, let me start checking things.
Start by taking off your clothes.
I'm going to use a magic item to take
pictures of every inch of your body for my records.
And let me cut off part of your body.
C-Cut off?
Yeah. I want to see if you feel pain.
D-Dunno...
I can prepare an anesthetic,
but will it work on you?
Then let's test that and a
bunch of other medical stuff!
We need to test your
sleep and appetite, too.
Find out for me if you can
eat normal food later.
And if you're closer to a vampire now...
Well, we can start our experiments tomorrow.
You must be tired today.
I do have a little bit of common
sense, you know. Once in a while.
Once in a while...
That's true. Once in a while.
I feel fine. Good, actually.
That strange impulse from yesterday is gone.
I can't go into the labyrinth
with my sword like this.
Clope will be so mad...
Hey.
What is this?
Your... sword.
You ruined it.
The materials are useless now.
I can't repair this.
I'm sorry... I imbued it with divinity.
That would explain the damage, but...
There are no enemies in the Labyrinth of the
Moon's Reflection that call for divinity.
I met a giant skeleton.
No way in hell did you—
No, you wouldn't lie about that.
But where?
I found an unexplored area.
Ren—
No... you.
Is that... true?
An unexplored area.
So that explains it.
I wondered why you looked so
weird when you came here.
So, did you get to explore it?
Not yet.
So I hate to ask, but I'd like that
sword I asked for as soon as possible.
I assume so.
You can't let the others explore it first.
But the sword you asked for isn't ready yet.
So I'll lend you another.
Really?
Yeah.
I'll give you something a little better.
You're one of our best customers, after all.
Yeah, I should've known I wouldn't fool him.
Well, he lent me a new sword.
I can't wait to get done in the labyrinth
and do another existential evolution.
Hey, give me all those veggies. All of them!
Can you come down a little
on the price of that meat?
I can't say no to Isabelle!
Okay, take the meat in the back, too!
Hooray!
The Red Dragon Tavern opens for lunch today!
Come and see us, everyone!
I definitely will!
Yeah, we'll be waiting for you!
Undead Adventurer